NICOLAI MANEV

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Summary

I am a full-stack developer with an eye for quality and professionalism. I believe that my 4 years of experience in web application development will let me make a valuable contribution to your projects.

Being a fast learner, I enjoy challenges that go beyond my knowledge set and am open to learning new technologies when necessary.

Experience

Finix LLC, Chicago | 2020 - Present

PHP Developer / Full Stack Developer

Developed a cloud-based wealth administration platform for alternative assets. Integrated third party accounting systems and e-signature providers. Refactored and optimized legacy code to ensure stability and scalability.

Team size: 9 people.

PHP • Laravel • MySQL • Docker • VueJS • Webpack • AdobeSign API • ATG • DocuSign API • Twilio

(finixsolutions.com)

BSS-ONE SRL, Chisinau | 2019 - 2020

PHP Developer / Full Stack Developer

Developed CRM systems and resource management platforms. Implemented database and filesystem encryption to secure important files and clients' identities. Among other things implemented document generation, document import, as well as role- and permission-based user access management.

Team size: 4 people.

PHP • Laravel • MySQL • Redis • PHPUnit • Docker • Webpack • VueJS • Pusher

(bss-one.ro)



Contact

- ★ Chisinau, Moldova
- **1** +37368541155
- ✓ nicolaimanev@gmail.com
- in /in/nicolaimanev

Skills

Programming

PHP
PHPUnit
Laravel
JavaScript
VueJS
MySQL
Python

Tools

Git Docker Trello Jira Linux

Other

Research Teaching Management (Scrum)

Languages

Russian English Romanian



Experience

Subsell SRL, Subsell SRL | 2018 - 2019

PHP Developer / Full Stack Developer

Developed a Shopify application that lets merchants increase their sales by providing extra features, unavailable in generic Shopify stores (cart recovery, upselling & downselling, A/B testing, custom theming, analytics, and many more). Developed Shopify PHP SDK.

Team size: 3 people.

PHP • Laravel • MySQL • Redis • PHPUnit • Docker • Webpack • VueJS • GrapesJS • Pusher • Shopify • ReCharge • Stripe • REST API • PayPal

(subsell.com)

OOK Group SRL, Chisinau | 2017 - 2018

PHP Developer / Full Stack Developer

Developed and supported a postcard website. Implemented various social web features such as user profile, friend lists, favourite postcards and sharing postcards with friends.

Team size: 4 people.

PHP • Laravel • MySQL • Redis • PHPUnit • Docker • Webpack • VueJS • oAuth • Mail Ru • OK Ru

(otkritkiok.ru)

Wisent Group LLC, Richardson | 2016 - 2017 Marketing Specialist

Worked on project development and promotion. Responsibilities included planning sales meetings, building partner relationships, developing and maintaining company's websites. Improved the company's client base and market presence. Expanded the scope of services by finding the right partners and creating win-win scenarios for multiple parties.

Team size: 5 people.

Python • Flask • Gulp • ¡Query • Docker

(wisentgroup.com)

Freelance, Chisinau | 2016 - 2016

PHP Developer / Full Stack Developer

Developed an online reviews management service for an Upwork client.

PHP · Laravel · MySQL · jQuery

(reviews.lk)

Interests

Music

I love my electric guitar and enjoy playing rock, jazz, blues. Sometimes I'm into classical music as well.

Creating

I'm fascinated by making things that work. I enjoy building programs for fun or to solve my personal problems.

Debating

I enjoy discussing over various topics. I perceive debates as a great way to learn or teach things.

Education

Bachelor of Management and Business Administration